Guide to the Carol Doherty Papers, 1979-1981 CTC.1992.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Carol Doherty Papers
1979-1992
CTC.1992.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
1.0 linear feet (2 boxes)
Carol Doherty, as part of her studies at Duquesne University Law School, wanted to examine the comparative structures of three theatres (American Shakespeare Festival, Royal Shakespeare Company, and Stratford Festival) and develop a model administrative plan. This collection contains the research she conducted which includes interviews and correspondence with several artistic/administrative persons at all three companies.
Doherty, Carol
Biography
Carol Doherty, a student at Duquesne University Law School, wanted to examine the comparative structures of three theatres: the American Shakespeare Festival, Royal Shakespeare Company, and Stratford Festival, in order to develop a model administrative plan. Her research included interviews and correspondence with several artistic/administrative persons at the companies, including most notably Peter Coe and Richard Bader of the American Shakespeare Theatre; David Brierly and Susan Fleetwood of the Royal Shakespeare Company; John Hays, Tom Patterson, and Rod Beattie of the Stratford Festival.
Arrangement
The papers are organized into two series. Additional scope and content notes are found after the series titles.
Series I. Research
Series II. "A Model Theatre"
Scope and Content Notes
These papers are centered around the research and development of Doherty's research project and paper, "A Model Theatre." Interestingly, included are descriptions of the American Shakespeare Theatre before the organization's demise and the Stratford Festival's internal struggles between 1979-1981.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These records were a gift of Carol Doherty in 1992.
Previous Citation
Carol Doherty Papers, 1983-1992, CTC.1992.01, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh.
Carol Doherty Papers, 1983-1992, CTC.26, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
American Shakespeare Festival Theatre and Academy. -- Management; American Shakespeare Theatre. -- Management; Brierly, David; Coe, Peter, 1929-1987; Duquesne University. School of Law.; Patterson, Tom, 1920-; Royal Shakespeare Company. -- Management; Stratford Festival (Stratford, Conn.). -- Management; Arts administrators -- Correspondence; Arts administrators -- Interviews; Centers for the performing arts -- Management; Centers for the performing arts -- United States; Correspondence; Drafts (Documents); Interviews; Notes; Records (Documents); Reports; Theater; Transcripts
- Research, I.
  Scope and Contents note
  This series holds correspondence, notes, interview transcripts, reports, etc. used to document the organization structures of the American Shakespeare Festival, the Stratford Festival, and the Royal Shakespeare Company. There is also one file containing research material sent from the Arts Council of Great Britain. This material was used to generate Ms. Doherty's paper "A Model Theatre".
  - American Shakespeare Theatre, 1.
    - Bader, Richard (Executive Director) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - By-Laws, December 1980 (Folder 2)
    - Campbell, Graeme (Actor) (Folder 3)
    - Coe, Peter (Artistic Director) (Folder 4)
    - Cooper, Roberta (Director of Planning) (Folder 5)
    - Coorman, William (Chairman, Board of Directors) (Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1981-82 (Folder 7)
    - Dotrice, Roy (Actor) (Folder 8)
    - Financial Statements, 1978-1980 (Folder 9)
    - Misc. Notes and Organizational Chart, 1981-82 (Folder 10)
    - Newman, Ellen (Folder 11)
    - Patria, Joe (Technical Manager) (Folder 12)
    - Pheneger, Richard (Director of marketing and Public Relations) (Folder 13)
    - Sheftis, Bob (Manager of Theatre Operations) (Folder 14)
    - Valente, Esther (Director of Financial Services) (Folder 15)
  - Arts Council of Great Britain, 2.
    - Arts Council of Great Britain, 1981 (Folder 16)
  - Royal Shakespeare Company, 3.
    - Agreement with Actor Equity Association, 1978 (Folder 17)
    - Book Excerpt (Folder 18)
    - Bowler, Simon (Deputy Technical Manager), September 1971 (Folder 19)
    - Brierly, David (General Manager), 1981 (Folder 20)
    - Charter and By-laws (Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, 1981-82 (Folder 22)
    - Godfrey, Derek (Folder 23)
    - Fleetwood, Susan (Actress) (Folder 24)
    - Malcolmson, Carole (Deputy Planning Controller), 1981 (Folder 25)
    - Notes, 1981 (Folder 26)
    - Organizational tree, May 1979 (Folder 27)
    - Reports, 1979-1981 (Folder 28)
  - Stratford Festival, Canada, 4.
    - Beattie, Rod (Actor) (Folder 29)
    - Benson, Susan (Head of Design) (Folder 30)
    - By-laws (Folder 31)
    - Corner, Gerry (Box Office Manager) (Folder 32)
    - Correspondence, 1979-1982 (Folder 33)
    - Hays, John (Executive Producer), August 1981 (Folder 34)
    - Job Descriptions, 1980-1982 (Folder 35)
    - Ladell, Dan (Archivist) (Folder 36)
    - Lawson, John (Chairman, Board of Governors) (Folder 37)
    - Misc. Notes and Reports, 1979-1984 (Folder 38-40)
    - Patterson, Tom (Founder) (Folder 41)
    - Power Struggle - newspaper clippings and notes regarding internal disputes, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Sherrin, Muriel (Producer) (Folder 2)
    - Schonberg, Michal (Literary Manager) (Folder 3)
    - Selby, Anne (Director of Publications and Publicity) (Folder 4)
    - Thomas, Gary (General Manager), 1981 (Folder 5)
    - Uren, John (Director of Marketing), 1981 (Folder 6)
- "A Model Theatre", II.
  This series consists of drafts, revisions and notes of Doherty's paper, "A Model Theatre."
  - General Information, 1981 (Folder 7)
  - Drafts, 1979-1981 (Folder 8-12)